Hi Sir, Good Morning Sir, my car has met with an
accident.  There is zero DAB insurance.
Invoice is also in add on.  She has become a total loss.
So sir what should be done?  Please
sir, please help me.  Sir, please
send me the format letter to the loan department.
How to do it?  Please provide its format.
So I said, Sir, please
send me your car insurance without it.
I can't say anything to you.  So brother
sent the insurance policy here.  This is
what you can see here
in the attached PDF.  After that I said, brother,
tell me whatever problem you have with your car at once, I will
guide you accordingly.  So
he said, brother, I have zero type insurance
with invoice. If my car meets with an accident,
then sir, it is a total loss.  Sir, friend is
demanding Rs 57,000.  He is saying
that brother, I will show him the total loss.
That's my job.  Its IDB value
is Rs 7,18,000 and the loan on it is Rs 5,37,000.
They are saying that the insurance amount will
come in 4 months and that too
in the bank account.  Before that, he will clear his loan and
give NOC.  You will get the remaining amount
in your account.  And this
process will take about 5 to 6 months.
He sent some photos of the car that met with the
accident.  Look brother, this
is a terrible accident.  This is the total loss.
So I replied to him that brother, he is
saying wrong things.  What Sarvere Sahib said is
wrong.  Now let us take a look at the policy
that they have sent.  This
is brother's policy.  So the policy is
from United India Insurance Company
as you can see here and the vehicle
is Tata Altros
2023 model vehicle and the ID of the vehicle is also
rightly said by brother that it is ₹718542
and here we come to its add
on, in the add on our full add on coverage
refer note 5 is fully attached.  Here
we will understand what add-ons
they have provided in the car.  So brother, there
is nil depreciation, there is consumers and there is key
replacement, there is engine protect and there is
return to invoice.  Look, the
premium for all has been paid,
here ₹1438 has been paid for return to invoice.  I have paid ₹1150 for the engine.
And my brother has
paid ₹750 for the replacement.  Consumer has
paid Rs 863.  And
₹4586 has been given as nil depreciation.  So this was the
policy of United India.  So, the entire discussion will be according to the policy that
we just saw and understood in WhatsApp chatting and
related to this, I
will explain everything to you in the entire video by giving examples of this, so
you have to watch the video till the end without skipping.
[Music]
Jai Hind friends.  Welcome back my channel.
As you saw the thumbnail of the video and got
attracted by the thumbnail and
clicked on the video.  Obviously you
are interested and some accident must have happened to you
or you want to gain your knowledge
or something similar has happened to someone in your friend circle, that is
why you came to this video, the
whole
video will be discussed as per the thumbnail, hence
you have to watch the video till the end without skipping, if the
video gets a little long then do
not mind that, now if you want to gain your knowledge then
I say in every video of mine
that look brother, getting insurance is
not a big deal, if we got cheap insurance, it does
not mean that
we have saved money.  The right
way, the right reason, the right thing to do to save money is to get
your claim settled timely in the true sense.
So as you saw in the thumbnail, the
car became a total loss.  Along with that, RTI
is attached as add-on in insurance
and plus there is also a loan on the car.  So
what are the systems in this condition and
how people are scammed
and how they are diverted,
you will understand all these things in today's video.  As you know I
share with you only those things which
I have done practically and I do not talk anything in the air.
Whatever videos I have on the channel related to motor
insurance renewal or motor insurance
tips or motor claim,
I have never
told you even a single point of it that is different from the IRDA guidelines,
nor will I ever tell you that, Insha Allah.  So
friends, what happened was that I got a curious
call from Haryana, a brother has a Tata Altros
car, his ID is also affixed for 71000 something,
you can see it on the insurance declaration value side, this is the entire
recording of his WhatsApp, this is what he said,
brother, my car has met with an
accident, there has been a major loss, I
took my car to the workshop or dealership,
where I had also got the insurance etc. done,
whichever company I went to, after that
when the surveyor came, the surveyor said, brother,
your car is
not in a condition to be repaired and there is a lot of damage in it
and it will not be fun to repair it, even if you repair it,
I will do one thing, I will get your car declared a total
loss, but for that you will have to make
some arrangements for me for
tea and water and the claim which will be settled for your car, it will take
you about 6 months, it may take
more, but you can assume 6 months
and ₹718000, your car's ID
is also affixed, 5375 out of ₹71000
Your loan is around ₹5,7075,000.  That loan will be
deducted from that ₹7,18,000 and you will get the remaining money i.e.
₹1.1 lakh or ₹1.5 lakh.
But you will have to wait for 6 months.  It may
take more time.
Now the query of that brother as you can
see recording happening on the side of WhatsApp.
It was like, friend, will it really take so much time
and sir, after checking my insurance, please
tell me how much time it will take for my car
and how much money will I get.  So when
I explained everything to him, I felt that
this work of diverting the mind does
not happen to just one person.  This happens to many
people.  Whoever is rich, it can happen to
anyone of yours.  With every person
who does not have information.  Anyone who is not aware of the
rules and regulations of IRDA related to motor claims can be
defrauded anywhere.  So that's why
I thought I should
make a particular video and
share with you all the things that I will tell them.
So the first thing is that brother, the
time of 6 months which the surveyor has told and
he said yes, okay sir, then the
time of 6 months which he has told is absolutely wrong, it is
completely against the guidelines and regulations of IRDA, it is wrong and the most
important thing that whatever expenses he has asked for for his tea and water, then those who
ask for this,
demand that give us this money, they are
shameful, disrespectful and naked type of
surveyors or any officer who makes such
demands.  Brother, the
insurance company is paying your travel expenses.
You are
not getting the settlement report as per the estimate,
you are getting your fees as per the estimate.  So
what do you need brother?  Why are you asking for
money from anyone?  Firstly, his car got
damaged.  She is worried about her life.  On
top of that you are asking for unnecessary money.
So this is wrong.  This is also wrong and it is
also wrong that it will take 6 months.
If any person from the insurance company or any surveyor tells you that it will take
6 months or 8 months to repair your vehicle, then
directly tell him that brother, have
you not read Regulation 156 of IRDA?
Where it is clearly written that
you have to give the claim of any vehicle within 30 days.  You have to
settle it and pay the money.  You have to settle the claim within a maximum of 30 days from the day
all the documents are submitted and
taken from the insured person.  I have to
make the payment to the guy.  If there is a
loan on the vehicle here, then it takes
some time for NOC, so let us
assume a maximum of 60 days, it does
not take more than this because the
insurance company will make the payment for the RC, you will get the
NOC from there, then you will go to the RTO and get the RC
cancelled, then it takes some time, so a
maximum of 60 days, not a single day extra will be taken on top of this, that is,
if the vehicle on loan has become a total loss and
its RC is being cancelled.  In that condition,
you have to get the claim settled within a maximum of 60 days, i.e. within 60 days, anyway.  This is the
regulation of IRDA.  You should directly
tell the surveyor that sir, have you
not increased the guidelines of IRDA?  So he will feel that this
guy knows something.  He will then
talk to you accordingly.  But when will you be
able to say this?  You will say this only when you yourself know
these things.  You understand it yourself.  People get
insurance done thinking that this has
never happened to us till date.  We take the car to a particular place
and always get the car insured
from there and park it there.
Our car gets the job done, friend.
Hey brother, it happens during repairing by moving it
up, down, forward and backward.  But one's
status becomes clear when the vehicle becomes a total
loss case.  There may be an accident, the
vehicle may get washed away in a flood, there may be a claim for theft of the vehicle
, it may get stolen or it may get set on fire
, the vehicle may get burnt.  There it
becomes clear who is in how much trouble.
How knowledgeable is the agent from whom you have taken the insurance.
How much is that insurance company
supporting you to which you have
paid a huge premium?  I have paid money
even after taking unnecessary ad down.  So then this becomes known.
If this ever happens to you, the
first thing you should do is
read the guidelines very carefully and
talk to the surveyor politely.  Brother, why are you telling me wrong
?  And what are you asking for money for
?  Why will it take so much time?  Take all
my papers and tell me if you need anything.
If you have a loan on your vehicle and the vehicle is facing a
total loss situation, then
contact the loan department at the earliest.  Because often people
complain that brother, it has been almost
6 months since I bought my car.  I am dying paying five
installments.  Absolutely
friend, what should I do?  Where should I give it from?  Friend brother, please get
my work settled.
Get the claim settled somehow.  So you have to
do all these things yourself.  But if you follow people like me, then
people take advantage of you by diverting your mind.
The day the car meets with an accident
and it becomes clear to you that the car has suffered
major damage and I am no longer in a condition to drive it.  It is
going into total loss.  You should immediately
go to the loan department there and give the
letter in writing by hand or
send it by mail and also go and meet them.  Send it on mail and
go and meet him and give him a hard copy also.
Attach the soft copy and mail it saying, brother,
my car met with an accident on
this date.  This is the car and this is my
loan number.  This is the insurance
policy number of the vehicle.  This is the vehicle number.   There
is so much loan on my car and I
am unable to pay it and I
request, plead, request, and
pray to you that you should
contact the insurance company, coordinate so that they make the
payment to you.  Whatever
loan I have, the final decision will be taken by the insurance company for which
I have taken insurance and on the basis of which
you have given me the money, brother, the loan is also being given after
seeing the insurance ID, they are
not giving it to you after seeing it, you are
saying that if you give ₹1 lakh, they will not give it, they will
give it as per the ID that is written, they have mortgaged the vehicle in a way, so they want to
get it from that, they have given
you the loan on the basis of that insurance, loan people also
harass only those who do not know
these things, tell them straight away, brother, you have
not given me the money after seeing this ID, they have given it after seeing the
insurance.  Now he will
give the money.  You have to take this.  The car is finished.
I don't have it.  So they
will coordinate with them and you have to give a letter to
your insurance company that brother,
I have a loan like this.  This is the loan number from this company.
Please coordinate with them.
Support me with the mouthful of
premium I gave you.  I have given it for this reason so that I can
keep my vehicle safe.  And
now you are needed.  Now you will support me.
I supported your company.   I
trusted you.
I took a policy from your company.  Now here is your turn.
Now it's your turn to support me.  So
brother, please support me.  I am not at all capable of paying any installments
, any EMIs.
So from here, whether
your car takes 4 months, 6 months
, or however many days it takes, at
least for that period you will not be under pressure
that you have to pay EMI.  So you
will be saved there.  From here your life is solved.  You will be at
peace that you are not bound to pay any
EMI every month, be it ₹2000 or ₹500 or ₹70000 or ₹5000.  It became
clear that brother, if the
insurance company makes the payment then it will be done from there only.
Well, what is the system now?
You should understand the entire principle of insurance company's claim.  This is about what to do as soon as an
accident happens.  As soon as your vehicle
claim becomes final.  The vehicle should be surveyed.
Exactly after a week, you
talk to the surveyor and say, brother, what happened sir, did
you submit the report of my vehicle or
not, he will say something or the other,
tell me the reason, what is it, where is the problem, if you
need any papers then
tell me, I will give them to you, if the surveyor's
reply is negative, not positive, then you
directly do this, attach your claim number,
your RC insurance, your DL, the
FIR report, all that,
and your loan number, etc., and put all the papers, put
your
customer care mail ID on your insurance policy
in the CC, and the main mail ID
you have to keep there, you have to keep the mail ID of your
insurance company's grievance department
there, you mail there, saying, sir, it has been
more than a week since I
gave you all the papers of my vehicle, yet the
report of my vehicle has not been submitted, and
if someone is demanding money from you, then
write openly that there is a
surveyor named so and so.  This is his number and he is
asking me for so much money.  And whatever you discuss with any
surveyor or insurance company, do it
in writing.  Even if
you are chatting with the surveyor on WhatsApp,
save it.  Take a screenshot.
Sometimes it happens that it flies away.   It
ends automatically.  There is a timer
system.  You can take a screenshot of it and keep it with
you.  Suppose the mobile gets
formatted or something happens, it will remain there.   Keep
taking photos etc. and keeping them in your sets.   Keep
saving.  Until your vehicle claim is
settled.  You will have to keep all these things.
So when you take all the things in return
, talk about them in return, then the person will be a little
aware and will reply to you everything with a little strictness and with a little
concern.
He will understand
that yes, the person in front is also not unknown.   He
is a knowledgeable man.  Knows things.
Friends, the Grievances Department
solves your case within 15 days.  Its maximum time is
15 days.  If you have received a negative reply from there also
and the matter is not getting resolved, then
without thinking twice, you should directly go
to IRDI and pick up their reply
and mail it there and when
your claim is settled, then as told to them
brother, you will get only the IDV of Rs. 718000.
So here also a lot of
fraud happens with many people that
your RTI is filed in insurance.
Return to invoice cover is attached.  Despite that,
you are being made a claim settler for the IDB amount.
Why is this being done
brother?  As told to this brother, to the
people of Haryana.  But if
you have taken RTI Return to Invoice cover.   If you have paid
its premium then the insurance
company will pay you the invoice amount of the vehicle.
That is, the ex-showroom price
plus road tax and your RTO
expenses, all these three things are added together and the
payment is made by adding the ex-showroom price, RTO and road tax, and that will be
paid to you by the insurance company.
As I mentioned this car,
Altros, I think
its bed is something around 9.20.10, but there
is also an ID of 78000. The surveyor
told this to them and the people there said that brother, out of
718000, your loan of ₹70.75000 will be
deducted, whereas this is wrong. The
main cost of the ₹91000 something that is being made is ₹18000. The
ID is also correct, but on the basis of RTI,
their invoice amount is to be made something of 910,
so 570 will be deducted from 9.10 and
they will get the remaining amount of around 3.60.70.  Now
how will you get this money here? You will get it in
two ways.  You will get it in your account
and the first money that will come to
you will be from the scrapped car, the
salvage car, the scrap car that
survived the accident, the insurance company will
sell it in the auction.  So, whoever
comes to pick it up, before picking it up, the
final deal is done and you get a mail
that brother, this is the salvage value of your scrap vehicle for so many rupees,
suppose
your salvage is going to be for ₹1 lakh brother
and we have deposited your loan amount of ₹570,
now your remaining ₹360000, you will get ₹1
lakh and the insurance company will
pay you ₹60000 in your account.  It happens this way.
So it is important for you to receive this mail.
If this mail is not received then you will be
stuck there and the insurance company
can then settle the amount with you on IDB.
Because surveyors show some great arrogance.
Not everyone does this in order to increase their number of points.  I am also
saying that people who are of low nature
do this.  So the insurance company has
done the dip.  Bhaiya settles it according to that report.
So the mail which I am talking about will be
your settlement mail, in that it will be
clearly written that your total amount IDV is
7,18,000 or whatever it is, I am
telling you that this is the
IDV of this vehicle, but on the basis of RTI,
your invoice amount which is to be made is ₹9,000
and ₹5,70,000 out of this your loan
deposit is something like 360, whatever it is.  Now
in this 360, your salvage of ₹1 lakh is gone.
260 we will give you.  After your salvage is lifted,
you will get money from there.
But when will we get it?  You will get this
when your money reaches the loan department.
From there you will get your NOC cleared.
You will go to RTO.  You will get
your RC cancelled with NOC there.
You will submit the cancellation letter to the insurance company.  Only
after that will you get it.   That's why
I am saying that the entire 60 days take
2 months.  But you have to remain active.
Now if you yourself are not active then not only in 60
days but they will not clear it even in 600 days
because they are lazy chickens, they have done
their work, the work is done, the matter is over, they are
sitting peacefully, on one hand if you feel
that something is left out, I have forgotten to tell
you something, I have given my WhatsApp number
in the description,
go there, save that number and
send your RC and your insurance, if
you have any such query, be it any
vehicle, tractor, truck, commercial
vehicle, private car, bike, anything, if
you are facing any such problem then
people like us are
always ready to serve you.  We will
provide you with a professional guide.
After taking this guide,
you will not need any advice from anyone.
By being self-dependent,
you
can get the complete settlement claim of your vehicle done on your own without
any hassle of anyone's advice.  If you
liked the video,
please like and visit the video.  Also, if you have come to the channel for the first time, then
subscribe to the channel and
share it with your friend circle.  Who
knows who might
need what and where.  If
you need any information related to your vehicle insurance renewal, then
you have 100% support for our claim settlement all over India.
If you want the best quotation
from the best insurance company, which will be best for you in your city,
your place, your state, your location.
We will provide you with that insurance company and
only with the compulsory add-ons and
not with the extra unnecessary add-ons.  So see you
in the next video
with the next topic.  Remember me in your prayers.
Jai Hind.